# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Remote Troubleshoots
Windows and Mac OS support
MAC and iOS support
Hardware and Software support
Cloning PCs
IT Asset Management
Technical Support
Handheld device management
Microsoft Suite L2/L3 support

## PERSONAL SKILLS

Creative spirit
Communication
Problem Solving
Customer Service Skill
Time management
Fast learner
Team Work skills

# PROFESSIONAL TOOLS

Python

Asset Explorer
SAP (Saas)
Sharepoint
Microsoft Visual Studio
Microsoft Office Suite
Service Desk Softwares
Tableau
Desktop Central
Android Studio

## ADARSH ANILKUMAR NAIR

## SENIOR IT ANALYST

#### **ABOUT ME**

My ambition behind opting Diploma in Information Technology and then Business Analytics as my Bachelor's Degree was to follow my Passion in the Business – IT sector. Having 4 years of experience in user/customer support roles have allowed me to learn various aspects of problem solving and enduser satisfaction. I'm currently working as a Service Desk Analyst at Deutsche Boerse. I have also worked as an IT Support Associate at Systems on Silicon Manufacturing Co. Pte. Ltd (TSMC subsidiary). New opportunities are always welcome by hoping to learn new adroitness and polishing existing skillsets.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### SERVICE DESK ANALYST

Deutsche Boerse | July 2021 - April 2022| Full Time

- Analysing in-house applications bug reports and providing support based on the bugs reported.
- Providing L2 / L3 support for software and system via phone calls, emails, remote sessions or face to face.
- Training users and clients for latest added applications, web services and technologies.
- Providing L2 support for Microsoft Suite and Windows OS. (7/8/10)
- Providing L1/L2 support for hardware, peripheral devices, printers, etc.
- Act as point of contact for Singapore branch's Tech related support.

#### PROCESS ASSOCIATE

Facebook | Jan 2020 - July 2021 | Fulltime in-house Contract

- To check applications' compliance, data security and privacy.
- Act as a Quality Tester for apps using Facebook Integrations.
- Providing Insights for Test cases, Reviewing.
- Identifying Compliance related problem within the app and highlight to the team
- Handling applications on IOS, Android and Web Apps.
- Identifying malicious apps that could potentially harm users' data and privacy, thereby providing safe and secure technology-environment to users.

### ASSOCIATE ENGINEER (IT SUPPORT)

Systems on Silicon Manufacturing Company Pte. Ltd. | July 2018- Dec 2019 | Full Time

- Responsible for attending incidents reported by the user. (to find root cause, and solve the issue remotely or on-site) and providing support accordingly via chat, email, Skype or face to face
- Dealt with more than 5000 user requests/incidents by using in-house CS tools
- Maintained IT Asset inventory. (includes Software and Hardware)
- Responsible for ordering and purchasing necessary assets for the company.
- Primary owner for IT Assets' Install, Move, Add, Change (IMAC) process.
- To create/update SOPs, Operational Instructions or other necessary documents to support the workflow.
- Provided training for Interns and New hires regarding the usage of company's IT asset
- Provided L1 support for Data Centre.

## INTERESTS/HOBBIES

Badminton Music Production Gaming Photography Football

#### CONTACT

: +65 81611321

🗹 : adirado.78@gmail.com

#### SOCIAL

## Linked in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/adarsh-a-nair-a25534112/

#### **EDUCATION**

#### BACHELOR OF BUSINESS STUDIES (HONOURS) BUSINESS ANALYTICS

University College Dublin (UCD) | 2020-2022

#### **DIPLOMA IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY**

Temasek Polytechnic | 2015 to 2018

#### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

- Trained a 3-person team in Singapore for Deutsche Boerse's IT service desk team
- Team lead for the project which involved the migration of 890 Office PCs and 310 Laptops from Windows 7 to Windows 10 OS.
- Hardware upgrade project for 310 office Laptops. (RAM Upgrade)
- Developed a dashboard to display all the details and the count of users in each Microsoft Active Directory group using ASP.NET (C# Web Forms).
- Structured SQL scripts, designed and built a database system to capture patient's medical records for a hospital which was done with SQL workbench.
- Developed an Android application which helps the students of Temasek Polytechnic to book venues in campus like library pod, Basketball court, Futsal court, etc. using Android Studio and jQuery. (Academic project)

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### 2019 EMPLOYEE RECOGNITION AWARD (SSMC PTE. LTD)

Company's Laptops which were damaged and decided to scrap were taken and extracted all the working hardwares. Later mixmatched all the extracted parts to build one laptop. Successfully refurbished 5x Toshiba Laptops (was 12x spoiled laptops which were out of warranty) with cost saving of SGD9k.

#### 2018 EMPLOYEE OF THE MONTH AWARD (SSMC PTE. LTD)

Took initiative to choose the best technology (hardware) by comparing and studying every product available in the market which fits for the every employees' type of usage.

## 2018-2019 SRC MEMBER FOR IT&A DEPARTMENT (SSMC PTE. LTD)

Along with the daily job, as an SRC member with two other colleagues, we planned and organised the IT&A department team outings/buildings for the year 2019.

## 2015-2016 MICROSOFT STUDENT PARTNER - MICROSOFT SINGAPORE

In the year 2015, I was selected as one of the Microsoft Student Partner from TemasekPolytechnic, where I got an opportunity to work for Microsoft Singapore. Along with my mates, we conducted Microsoft Azure workshops in our campus and involved in various other activities conducted by Microsoft Singapore.